pcisecuritystandards.org 2019-05-11

# Privacy Policy

**Last Updated: 8 June 2018**

Your privacy is important to the PCI Security Standards Council. Our goal is to provide you with a personalized online experience that provides you with the information, resources, and services that are most relevant and helpful to you. This PCI Security Standards Council Online Privacy Statement (the "Privacy Statement") has been written to describe the conditions under which this web site and other online PCI Security Standards Council resources (the "Web site") are being made available to you. The Privacy Statement discusses, among other things, how data obtained during your visit to this Web site may be collected and used. We strongly recommend that you read the Privacy Statement carefully. By using this Web site, you agree to be bound by the terms of this Privacy Statement. If you do not accept the terms of the Privacy Statement, you are directed to discontinue accessing or otherwise using the Web site or any materials obtained from it. If you are dissatisfied with the Web site, by all means contact us at [info@pcisecuritystandards.org](mailto:info@pcisecuritystandards.org); otherwise, you should disconnect from this site and refrain from visiting the site in the future. 

The process of maintaining a Web site is an evolving one, and the PCI Security Standards Council may decide at some point in the future, without advance notice, to modify the terms of this Privacy Statement. Your use of the Web site, or materials obtained from the Web site, indicates your assent to the Privacy Statement at the time of such use. The effective Privacy Statement will be posted on the Web site, and you should check upon every visit for any changes. 

#### **Sites Covered by this Privacy Statement**

This Privacy Statement applies to all PCI Security Standards Council- maintained Web sites, domains, information portals, registries and other online resources, and PCI Security Standards Council may from time to time require users of specific portals or other resources to agree to corresponding additional terms and conditions. If the terms of this Privacy Statement conflict with such other terms and conditions, such other terms and conditions shall govern to the extent necessary to resolve such conflicts.

#### **Children's Privacy**

The PCI Security Standards Council is committed to protecting the privacy needs of children, and we encourage parents and guardians to take an active role in their children's online activities and interests. The PCI Security Standards Council does not intentionally collect information from children under the age of 13, and the PCI Security Standards Council does not target its Web site to children.

#### **Links to Non-PCI Security Standards Council Web Sites**

The PCI Security Standards Council's Web site may provide links to third- party Web sites for the convenience of our users. If you access those links, you will leave the PCI Security Standards Council's Web site. The PCI Security Standards Council does not control these third-party Web sites and cannot represent that their policies and practices will be consistent with this Privacy Statement. For example, other Web sites may collect or use personal information about you in a manner different from that described in this document. Therefore, you should use other Web sites with caution, and you do so at your own risk. We encourage you to review the privacy policy of any Web site before submitting personal information.

#### **TYPES OF INFORMATION WE COLLECT**

**Non-Personal Information**

Non-personal information is data about usage and service operation that is not directly associated with a specific personal identity. The PCI Security Standards Council may collect and analyze non-personal information to evaluate how visitors use the PCI Security Standards Council Web site.

#### **Aggregate Information**

The PCI Security Standards Council may gather aggregate information, which refers to information your computer automatically provides to us and which cannot be tied back to you as a specific individual. Examples include referral data (the Web sites you visited just before and just after our site), the pages viewed, time spent at our Web site, and Internet Protocol (IP) addresses. An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you access the Internet. For example, when you request a page   from one of our sites, our servers log your IP address to create aggregate reports on user demographics and traffic patterns and for purposes of system administration. 

#### **Log Files**

Every time you request or download a file from the Web site, the PCI Security Standards Council may store data about these events and your IP address in a log file. The PCI Security Standards Council may use this information to analyze trends, administer the Web site, track users' movements, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use or for other business purposes. 

#### **Cookies**

Our site may use a feature of your browser to set a "cookie" on your computer. Cookies are small packets of information that a Web site's computer stores on your computer. The PCI Security Standards Council's Web site can then read the cookies whenever you visit our site. We may use cookies in a number of ways, such as to save your password so you don't have to re-enter it each time you visit our site, to deliver content specific to your interests and to track the pages you've visited. These cookies allow us to use the information we collect to customize your PCI Security Standards Council experience so that your visit to our site is as relevant and as valuable to you as possible.

Most browser software can be set up to deal with cookies. You may modify your browser preference to provide you with choices relating to cookies. You have the choice to accept all cookies, to be notified when a cookie is set or to reject all cookies. If you choose to reject cookies, certain of the functions and conveniences of our Web site may not work properly, and you may be unable to use those PCI Security Standards Council services that require registration in order to participate, or you will have to re-register each time you visit our site. Most browsers offer instructions on how to reset the browser to reject cookies in the "Help" section of the toolbar. We do not link non-personal information from cookies to personally identifiable information without your permission

#### **Web Beacons**

The PCI Security Standards Council's Web site also may use Web beacons to collect non-personal information about your use of our Web site and the Web sites of selected sponsors and advertisers, your use of special promotions or newsletters, and other activities. The information collected by Web beacons allows us to statistically monitor how many people are using our Web site and selected sponsors' sites; how many people open our emails; and for what purposes these actions are being taken. Our Web beacons are not used to track your activity outside of our Web site or those of our sponsors. The PCI Security Standards Council does not link non-personal information from Web beacons to personally identifiable information without your permission. 

#### **Personal Information**

Personal information (“Personal Data”) is information that is associated with your name or personal identity. In general, the PCI Security Standards Council uses personal information to better understand your needs and interests and to provide you with better service. The specific uses for Personal Data collected on the site is described on the pages where such data is collected.  The types of personal information you provide to us on these pages may include name, address, phone number, email address, user IDs, passwords, and billing information.  By providing this information, you are able to request and/or download information or materials, subscribe to mailing lists, participate in online discussions, collaborate on documents, provide feedback, submit information into registries, register for events, apply for participation or membership, or join technical committees or working groups.  We collect this information so we can contact you or send you requested materials (such as with requested documents or subscriptions to mailing lists) and to identify you to us or others (such as applications to register for events or join committees, or to participate in online discussions), and to bill you for requested services or materials. You may always elect not to provide your Personal Data to us, but that will limit your ability to participate in these activities or benefit from these services. 

Personal Data will not be kept for longer than is necessary for the purpose (s) for which it was collected, and in general, we will retain Personal Data for a period of 3 years, or if you have any qualification or contractual relationship with us, for a period of 3 years after cessation of that qualification or relationship.  In some cases it is not possible for us to specify in advance the periods for which your personal data will be retained. Notwithstanding this, we may retain your Personal Data where such retention is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another person. 

#### **Restricted Web Sites and Portals**

Information you provide in connection with applying for participation or membership is used to create a corresponding participating organization or member profile, and may be shared with other PCI Security Standards Council member or participant representatives and organizations. Such information may be provided to other participants or members on a secure Web site to encourage and facilitate collaboration, research, and the free exchange of information. PCI Security Standards Council participants and members automatically are added to applicable PCI Security Standards Council mailing lists. From time to time, participant and member information may be shared with event organizers and/or other organizations that provide additional benefits to PCI Security Standards Council participants or members. By providing us with your personal information, you expressly consent to our storing, processing, and distributing such information for these purposes.

#### **Company Information**

Company information is information that is associated with the name and address of PCI Security Standards Council participant or member organizations and may include data about usage and service operation. The primary representative of any such organization may request usage reports to gauge the extent of their employees' involvement in consortium activities. You should be aware that information regarding your participation in technical committees or working groups, for example, may be made available to your company's primary representative and to PCI Security Standards Council staff members.

#### **HOW WE USE YOUR INFORMATION**

The PCI Security Standards Council may use non-personal data that is aggregated for reporting about PCI Security Standards Council Web site usability, performance, and effectiveness. It may be used to improve the experience, usability, and content of the site.

The PCI Security Standards Council may use personal information to offer or provide services that support its activities or those of PCI Security Standards Council participants or members, and their collaboration with PCI Security Standards Council, or to provide you with electronic newsletters, announcements, surveys or other information. When accessing restricted PCI Security Standards Council Web pages and portals, your personal user information may be tracked in order to support collaboration, ensure authorized access, and enable communication among participants or members. 

#### **Information Sharing**

The PCI Security Standards Council does not sell, rent, or lease any individual's personal information or lists of email addresses to anyone for marketing purposes, and we take commercially reasonable steps to maintain the security of this information. However, the PCI Security Standards Council reserves the right to supply any such information to any organization into which the PCI Security Standards Council may merge in the future or to which it may make any transfer in order to enable a third party to continue part or all of the Council's mission. We also reserve the right to release personal information to protect our systems or business, when we reasonably believe you to be in violation of our Terms of Use or if we reasonably believe you to have initiated or participated in any illegal activity. In addition, please be aware that in certain circumstances, the PCI Security Standards Council may be obligated to release your personal information pursuant to judicial or other government subpoenas, warrants, or other orders.

In keeping with our open process, the PCI Security Standards Council may maintain publicly accessible archives for the vast majority of our activities. For example, posting an email message to any PCI Security Standards Council-hosted mail list or discussion forum, subscribing to any PCI Security Standards Council newsletter or registering for one of our public meetings may result in your email address becoming part of the publicly accessible archives.

If you are a PCI Security Standards Council participant or member, you should be aware that some items of your personal information may be visible to other PCI Security Standards Council participants and members, and to   the public. The PCI Security Standards Council participant and member databases may retain information about your name, email address, company affiliation and such other personal address and identifying data as you choose to supply. That data may be generally visible to other PCI Security Standards Council participants or members, and to the public. Your name, email  address, and other information you may supply also may be associated in the PCI Security Standards Council's publicly accessible records with the PCI Security Standards Council's various committees, working groups, and similar activities that you join, in various places, including: (i) the permanently-posted attendance and other records of those activities; (ii) documents generated by the activity, which may be permanently archived; and, (iii) along with message content, in the permanent archives of the PCI Security Standards Council's email lists, which also may be public.

Please remember that any information (including personal information) that you disclose in public areas of our Web site, such as forums, message boards, and news groups, becomes public information that others may collect, circulate, and use. Because we cannot and do not control the acts of others, you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose information about yourself or others in public forums such as these.

Given the international scope of the PCI Security Standards Council, personal information may be visible to persons outside your country of residence, including to persons in countries that your own country's privacy laws and regulations deem deficient in ensuring an adequate level of protection for such information. If you are unsure whether this privacy statement is in conflict with applicable local rules, you should not submit your information. If you are located within the European Union, you should note that your information will be transferred to the United States, which is deemed by the European Union to have inadequate data protection. Nevertheless, in accordance with local laws implementing European Union Directive 95/46/EC of 24 October 1995 on the protection of individuals with regard to the processing of personal data and on the free movement of such data ("EU Privacy Directive"), individuals located in countries outside of the United States of America who submit personal information do thereby consent to the general use of such information as provided in this Privacy Statement and to its transfer to and/or storage in the United States of America.

Your Personal Data will never be used for direct marketing purposes, although we may contact you to follow up on a request you made for information about a service, event or activity we provide.

If you do not want your personal information collected and used by the PCI Security Standards Council, please do not visit the PCI Security Standards Council's Web site or apply for participation status.

#### **Access to and Accuracy of Information**

The PCI Security Standards Council is committed to keeping the personal information of our participating and member organizations accurate. All the information you have submitted to us can be verified and changed. In order to do this, please email us a request at [info@pcisecuritystandards.org. ](mailto:info@pcisecuritystandards.org)We may provide participants and/or members with online access to their own personal profiles, enabling them to update or delete information at any time. To protect your privacy and security, we also may take reasonable steps to verify identity, such as requiring a user ID and password, before access to modify personal profile data. Certain areas of the PCI Security Standards Council's Web sites may limit access to specific individuals through the use of passwords or other personal identifiers; a password prompt is your indication that a restricted resource is being accessed.

#### **Security**

The PCI Security Standards Council uses a variety of means to protect personal information provided by users of the Web site, including using firewalls and other security measures on its servers. No server, however, is 100% secure, and you should take this into account when submitting personal or confidential information about yourself on any Web site, including this one. Much of the personal information is used in conjunction with participation and/or member-level services such as collaboration and discussion, so some types of personal information such as your name, company affiliation, and email address will be visible to other the PCI   Security Standards Council participants or members, and to the public. The PCI Security Standards Council assumes no liability for the interception, alteration, use or misuse of the information you provide. You alone are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your personal information. Please use care when you access this Web site and provide personal information.

#### **Opting Out**

From time to time the PCI Security Standards Council may email you electronic newsletters, announcements, surveys or other information. If you prefer not to receive any or all of these communications, you may opt out by following the directions provided within the electronic newsletters and announcements.

**General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) Compliance**

If you are a resident of or are located in the European Economic Area (“EEA”), you may also have certain rights under the General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”).  Personal Data you provide on any of the PCI Security Standards Council’s sites is only collected with your consent, and may be transmitted outside of the EEA to the PCI Security Standards Council (or computer servers maintained for the benefit of the PCI Security Standards Council) pursuant to that consent. 

In general, under the GDPR you may:

  * request access to your Personal Data
  * have incomplete or incorrect data corrected
  * have your Personal Data deleted
  * suspend or restrict our use of your Personal Data, or withdraw your consent
  * request a copy of your Personal Data
  * complain to a supervisory authority if you believe your rights under the GDPR are not being respected

Should you request a copy of your Personal Data, we will supply to you a copy of your personal data. The first copy will be provided free of charge, but additional copies may be subject to a reasonable fee.  Should you request the deletion of your Personal Data, PCI Security Standards Council will generally do so as soon as practicable, although your right to have your Personal Data deleted is subject to exceptions, such as, for example, compliance with a legal obligation or for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims. 

If you consider that our processing of your personal information infringes data protection laws, you have a legal right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority responsible for data protection. You may do so in the EU member state of your habitual residence, your place of work or the place of the alleged infringement.

Contact the PCI Security Standards’ Council, through its Data Protection Program at [dataprivacy@pcisecuritystandards.org](mailto:dataprivacy@pcisecuritystandards.org) if you have concerns regarding your Personal Data, or wish to exercise any of these listed rights.

Note that, if you are in the EEA, we may transfer your Personal Data outside of the EEA, including to the United States.  By way of example, this may happen if your Personal Data is transferred to our servers located in a country outside of the EEA. These countries may not have similar data protection laws to the EEA. By submitting your Personal Data, you’re agreeing to this transfer, storing or processing. If we transfer your information outside of the EEA in this way, we will take steps to ensure that appropriate security measures are taken with the aim of ensuring that your privacy rights continue to be protected as outlined in this policy.

#### **Contacting Us**

Questions about this Privacy Statement can be directed to [info@pcisecuritystandards.org](mailto:info@pcisecuritystandards.org).
